[{"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c1f3", "question": "What year marked the debut of the Volkswagen Golf GTI?", "answer": "1976", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c80a", "question": "What scientist was also the sixth abbot of Brno's Abbey of Saint Thomas?", "answer": "Gregor Mendel", "category": "science"}, {"id": "6015f78efe83fe1f2a824c22", "question": "When was the fast food chain, Mcdonalds, founded?", "answer": "Mcdonald's was founded on April 15th, 1955 in Des Plaines, Illinois.", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c1ec", "question": "What is added to cognac and absinthe to make a Sazerac cocktail?", "answer": "Sugar cube and Peychaud's bitters", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133af23", "question": "In which battle was Horatio Nelson killed?", "answer": "Battle of Trafalgar", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a2d3", "question": "Who played the role of Tracy Samantha Lord in the 1956 film \"High Society\"?", "answer": "Grace Kelly", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338fb3", "question": "Who painted \"The Blue Boy\"?", "answer": "Thomas Gainsborough", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5feccfbbec223966ae8f88b8", "question": "What was Cecil B. DeMille's first film to be nominated for the Academy Award for Best Picture?", "answer": "\"Cleopatra\"", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a2ea", "question": "What year did the band Human League initially release the album entitled \"Reproduction\"?", "answer": "1979", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339821", "question": "Who played Dolly Levi in the film adaptation of \"Hello Dolly\"?", "answer": "Barbra Streisand", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5909d0acbb53d1af658864fd", "question": "What car did Frank buy for himself for Christmas in Season 6 of the TV show \"It\u2019s Always Sunny in Philadelphia\"?", "answer": "Lamborghini Countach", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133bbfa", "question": "What brand of cigarettes were a major sponsor in Formula One racing?", "answer": "Marlboro", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c7cc", "question": "What bird is Britain's VTOL \"jump jet\" named for?", "answer": "The Harrier hawk", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b9bd", "question": "The Mario villain \"Wario\", made his first appearance in which Nintendo game?", "answer": "Super Mario Land 2", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339d7c", "question": "What Top Gun actor loses his left arm in the movies \"Total Recall\" and \"Starship Troopers\"?", "answer": "Michael Ironside", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5efa96f2ccb363a2cbc5227d", "question": "How many people helped direct the 2019 season of \"The Mandalorian\"?", "answer": "5", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "58c8a84290aac110e416708d", "question": "Who said \"He that drinks his cider alone, let him catch his horse alone.\"?", "answer": "Benjamin Franklin", "category": "history"}, {"id": "58c9f766b4e2c7fbd3896748", "question": "What company\u2019s tea shipment was destroyed during the Boston Tea Party in 1773?", "answer": "East India Company", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b8c4", "question": "What is the Japanese alcoholic drink sake made from?", "answer": "Rice", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133aae0", "question": "What is the capital of Sudan?", "answer": "Khartoum", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5ffa57fbc73aa70ea0b70b37", "question": "Which U.S. state features the Italian phrase \"Fatti maschii, parole femine\" as its state motto?", "answer": "Maryland  (The motto translates as \u201cManly deeds, womanly words.\u201d\u00a0 The state uses\u00a0\"Strong deeds, gentle words\".)", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5fd66bf8a5bfecdd737e088c", "question": "What was the original name of Vaseline?", "answer": "Wonder jelly", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a47d", "question": "Which city can you find the headquarters of Interpol?", "answer": "Lyon", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133bd37", "question": "Who scored the famous \"Hand of God\" goal in the 1986 World Cup?", "answer": "Diego Maradona", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5fea3d5dff048f679a45ab4b", "question": "What is the tendency of Earth's rotation to turn winds called?", "answer": "Coriolis Effect", "category": "science"}, {"id": "58ab97ef86faa38a764be52c", "question": "How many cars had to be stolen in the 2000 film remake of \"Gone in 60 Seconds\"?", "answer": "50", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5b358d9f5db0d66a186cb562", "question": "Pat Sullivan is often credited with creating which cartoon character?", "answer": "Felix the Cat", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b7ea", "question": "What are the two most common coffee bean types?", "answer": "Arabica and Robusta", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133bddd", "question": "What children's game takes its name from the Swahili word for \"build\"?", "answer": "Jenga", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5ffa3c19c73aa70ea0b70aea", "question": "Angostura bitters are named for a town in what country?", "answer": "Venezuela", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5fdc0c6a469bb8041d07a050", "question": "What is a group of witches called?", "answer": "A coven", "category": "general"}, {"id": "601b4c0e49076251badbeacc", "question": "Who got married in the very first White House wedding?", "answer": "Dolley Madison\u2019s sister -- Lucy Payne Washington, the sister of First Lady Dolley Madison, married Thomas Todd in 1819.", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338dc1", "question": "Who had a best seller at age 84 with her autobiography \"Me: Stories of My Life\"?", "answer": "Katharine Hepburn", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b9cc", "question": "What is the name of the badge you get in Pokemon from Saffron gym?", "answer": "Marsh Badge", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b396", "question": "Which car company was founded by Sir William Lyons in 1922?", "answer": "Jaguar", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5c77cd7424f0f7a362efd542", "question": "How man men have walked on the moon as of December 31, 2018?", "answer": "12", "category": "science"}, {"id": "597cda28e347d002c297e4d2", "question": "What is the name of the Chinese leader who died in 1997?", "answer": "Deng Xiaoping", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c763", "question": "What kind of animal lives in a \"warren\"?", "answer": "Rabbit", "category": "science"}, {"id": "600b86681d8c1817608d53e4", "question": "What does the \"E\" stand for in Chuck E. Cheese?", "answer": "Entertainment (Restaurant founder, Nolan Bushnell, happens to be the founder of Atari.)", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311339330", "question": "What actor played the role of Captain John McIntyre on the TV show \"M*A*S*H\"?", "answer": "Wayne Rogers", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339bbf", "question": "What popular designer was responsible for the wardrobe of \"His Wife & Her Lover\"?", "answer": "Jean Paul Gaultier", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f03113396b6", "question": "Which Californian national park shares its name with a U2 album?", "answer": "Joshua Tree National Park", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "600f6eeaa9e54d890926f6cc", "question": "In which country can you find the world's tallest twin building?", "answer": "Malaysia -- The Petronas Twin Towers in Kuala Lumpur are 1,483 feet tall and have a 400 ft. solid foundation, the world's largest.", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133bc4c", "question": "Who is credited with inventing Coca-Cola?", "answer": "John Pemberton", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133aa26", "question": "What ocean separates North America from Europe?", "answer": "Atlantic", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338b1f", "question": "What place did Dante describe as having \"Abandon hope, all ye who enter here\" written over its doors?", "answer": "Hell", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "590678c2ff9c0647b50a804c", "question": "The year 2016 was the 2016th year of what Civil calendar?", "answer": "Gregorian calendar", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311339456", "question": "What film earned Henry Fonda his first Oscar for Best Actor?", "answer": "On Golden Pond", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c0e1", "question": "Calamarata pasta is shaped like what?", "answer": "Wide rings", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5ede129f031133c8f6", "question": "What units are ship speeds measured in?", "answer": "Knots", "category": "science"}, {"id": "601b4af249076251badbeabe", "question": "Ruby Bridges became the first Black student to do what?", "answer": "At six-years-old, Ruby Bridges was the first Black child to be integrated into an all-white school in New Orleans in 1960.", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f031133a147", "question": "Who sang the title song to the 1964 James Bond film \"Goldfinger\"?", "answer": "Shirley Bassey", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133ab0d", "question": "What is the capital of Greece?", "answer": "Athens", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133abee", "question": "What is the capital of Ukraine?", "answer": "Kiev", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5fd6607ba5bfecdd737e0834", "question": "What is the largest gathering of people in the world?", "answer": "The Kumbh Mela in India", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339c8c", "question": "Who was engaged to magician David Copperfield for six years in the 1990's?", "answer": "Claudia Schiffer", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338c0d", "question": "What novel won Alice Walker a Pulitzer Prize in 1983?", "answer": "The Color Purple", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133ae49", "question": "Who was the first person to sign the Declaration of Independence?", "answer": "John Hancock", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133aec9", "question": "Who was the US vice-president during the presidency of Bill Clinton?", "answer": "Al Gore", "category": "history"}, {"id": "594d057b1a1c922dd1ac64a2", "question": "What is Ronald Biggs famous for?", "answer": "Being one of the \"Great Train Robbers\"", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f031133a0a9", "question": "What is Goldfinger's first name?", "answer": "Auric", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5fd2d0e12596a59cbdfbd382", "question": "Which country was the first to enact daylight savings time?", "answer": "Germany", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a8e9", "question": "What island in Manila Bay was the site of a famous 1942 siege?", "answer": "Corregidor", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "59071f8a3745b36be73039eb", "question": "The comic book series \"Revival\" is often described as what literary genre?", "answer": "Horror/Rural-noir", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b0c4", "question": "Which number King Louis was king of France when the storming of the Bastille took place?", "answer": "XVI", "category": "history"}, {"id": "6018bd8bd96d05b23b28165c", "question": "Atropos, Lachesis, and Clotho are the Three what of Greek mythology?", "answer": "Fates", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339689", "question": "In the TV show \"The Simpsons\", what is the name of Mr. Burns' stuffed bear?", "answer": "Bobo", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c680", "question": "Organic chemistry is centered around what two elements?", "answer": "Carbon and Hydrogen", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5fe8b66501dd7bf43be5e7db", "question": "What kind of animal is a hellbender?", "answer": "Salamander", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5fe73524eec85e375820b245", "question": "What famous dog belonged to Richard M. Nixon when he was a U.S. Senator in the early 1950s?", "answer": "Checkers", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c441", "question": "What is the molten rock magma called once it flows from a volcano?", "answer": "Lava", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b75a", "question": "What is the name of the baby depicted on the Sacagawea dollar coin?", "answer": "Pomp", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133bb02", "question": "Who knocked out Trevor Berbick in 1986 to become the WBC Heavyweight Champion in boxing?", "answer": "Mike Tyson", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b44b", "question": "On August 2, 1876, Jack McCall gunned down which famous lawman?", "answer": "Wild Bill Hickok", "category": "history"}, {"id": "58f16a4af7c52aae91cc07da", "question": "Who is Prospero's daughter in Shakespeare's \"The Tempest\"?", "answer": "Miranda", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5fe775cceec85e375820b311", "question": "What U.S. city has an airport named after a President and First Lady?", "answer": "Little Rock, Arkansas", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339ecf", "question": "What animated film begins in Shiverpool, Antarctica?", "answer": "Surf's Up", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "592201b0a4edfd43a087addb", "question": "What is the first name of the fictional character \"Miss Marple\"?", "answer": "Jane", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f031133959c", "question": "Who plays the broken-hearted widower in the 2003 movie \"Love Actually\"?", "answer": "Liam Neeson", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133bcd5", "question": "In England, what is governed by the FA?", "answer": "Soccer", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c55e", "question": "What is the name for the longest side of a right-angled triangle?", "answer": "Hypotenuse", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c325", "question": "What does the acronym RPM stand for?", "answer": "Revolutions per minute", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5fe6aaa420565ad31a57c81d", "question": "What kind of planes were used in the Doolittle Raid?", "answer": "B-25 bombers", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5fe0e327fcbed638185eaa21", "question": "Which South American country is known as the \"Land of Poets\"?", "answer": "Chile", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "597cddb5e347d002c297e4f3", "question": "Which 1960s singer/songwriter was voted \"Ugliest Man on Campus\" while attending college?", "answer": "Janis Joplin", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5fe52ef81bf59ab7d2e38110", "question": "What is the name for a drink of half iced tea and half lemonade?", "answer": "Arnold Palmer", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd58de129f03113388e0", "question": "Who wrote the first three books of the \"Millennium\" novel series?", "answer": "Stieg Larsson", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338e5e", "question": "What literary work inspired the Beatles' \"Tomorrow Never Knows\" song?", "answer": "The Tibetan Book of the Dead", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133bd5f", "question": "In Britain, what kind of meat comes in rashers?", "answer": "Bacon", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f03113392ba", "question": "What color was Oscar in the first season of \"Sesame Street\"?", "answer": "Orange", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339cd7", "question": "\"A Christmas Story\" was inspired by the childhood reminiscences of what radio personality?", "answer": "Jean Shepherd", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c517", "question": "What is a cross between a blackberry and a raspberry?", "answer": "Boysenberry", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c05c", "question": "Which natural phenomenon can be measured on the Mercalli scale?", "answer": "Earthquakes", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5fe25938658e585fda9cfa41", "question": "What shape is \"chiocciole\" pasta?", "answer": "Snail", "category": "general"}, {"id": "59f9b937364247bf200fb889", "question": "Who made the song \"A Boy Named Sue\" popular in 1969?", "answer": "Johnny Cash", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "59071f1e3745b36be73039e8", "question": "What is the full name of Em Cypress, Dana's sister and reviver, in the comic book series \"Revival\"?", "answer": "Martha Ann Cypress", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133bb44", "question": "At what university did Tiger Woods play collegiate golf for two years before turning pro?", "answer": "Stanford", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133ae47", "question": "What were the Americans who supported the British during the American Revolution known as?", "answer": "Loyalists", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5fe9f0f2ff048f679a45aaac", "question": "Wiccaphobia is the fear of what?", "answer": "Witches and witchcraft", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b45f", "question": "Who received a patent for the first electric razor in 1930?", "answer": "Jacob Schick", "category": "history"}, {"id": "58d116db4fea7fe947a22273", "question": "From what Gaelic word is \"Dublin\" derived?", "answer": "Dublind", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133ae3d", "question": "What slogan did Nancy Reagan create for her drug awareness campaign?", "answer": "Just Say No", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd58de129f031133890f", "question": "Who wrote \"Treasure Island\"?", "answer": "Robert Louis Stevenson", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339e46", "question": "What athlete had a part in the movie \"The Scorpion King\"?", "answer": "The Rock", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c3c3", "question": "What is the name for a baby turkey?", "answer": "Poult", "category": "science"}, {"id": "6002436e4be4723ccac22196", "question": "In Jonathan Swift\u2019s \"Gulliver\u2019s Travels\", what is the name of the island inhabited by tiny people?", "answer": "Lilliput", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338e19", "question": "In what 1979 novel is the \"Thumb\" device actually a Sub-Etha Sens-O-Matic?", "answer": "The Hitchhiker's Guide to the Galaxy", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339905", "question": "In what movie does Jack Nicholson\u2019s character describe woman as men without \u201creason and accountability\u201d?", "answer": "As Good As It Gets", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5a4a98fa61d1b4d384d5d694", "question": "What year did the radio show \"Gunsmoke\" debut as a TV show?", "answer": "1955", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133ae02", "question": "Who was the first human in outer space?", "answer": "Yuri Gagarin", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5fe7350aeec85e375820b242", "question": "What was the name of President Lyndon B. Johnson's wife?", "answer": "Claudia Alta \"Lady Bird\" Johnson", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339bb1", "question": "In 1926, the funeral of what silent movie star attracted a crowd of nearly 100,000 people to view the remains?", "answer": "Rudolph Valentino", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5ffa43aac73aa70ea0b70b19", "question": "In which country can you find a beach that resembles a \"golden horn\"?", "answer": "Croatia", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f031133a124", "question": "What do the prisoners call the escape tunnels in the film \"The Great Escape\"?", "answer": "Tom, Dick and Harry", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f03113389cf", "question": "What book of short stories has a second section called \"Kaa's Hunting\"?", "answer": "The Jungle Book", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5ede129f031133c9c5", "question": "Venation is used to describe what item found in nature?", "answer": "Leaves", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5fef31f16ce05a3942286dfe", "question": "The Bronze Age was characterized by an alloy consisting of which two metals?", "answer": "Copper and tin", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5ed43e06d244b1771b64500d", "question": "In what year was the Solidarity union founded in Poland?", "answer": "1980", "category": "History"}, {"id": "5867fd5ede129f031133ca36", "question": "Which element is second on the periodic table?", "answer": "Helium", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f031133a034", "question": "In the show \"Family Guy\", which US president has been seen happily singing in public about being nude?", "answer": "Bill Clinton", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c1d0", "question": "Which bar is the Grasshopper cocktail is said to have originated from?", "answer": "Tujague's", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5fdc1191469bb8041d07a076", "question": "Which red wine varietal is nicknamed the \"King of Grapes\"?", "answer": "Cabernet Sauvignon", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339a74", "question": "Matt Dillon and Kitty Russell were long-running characters on what TV series?", "answer": "Gunsmoke", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "58ab14a5baab681b09292177", "question": "What year did GM first introduce the Corvette?", "answer": "1953", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5902a0f0cad1ec93f27df772", "question": "What do you ferment to make kombucha?", "answer": "Sweetened tea", "category": "general"}, {"id": "6015df92fe83fe1f2a824b7b", "question": "Who was the first female surgeon in the U.S. Army?", "answer": "Mary Edwards Walker", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5a4a975661d1b4d384d5d683", "question": "Where would you find a \"crossbuck\"?", "answer": "At a railroad crossing", "category": "general"}, {"id": "6014c7aafbde8045e48466c6", "question": "What is the only marsupial found in the U.S. and Canada?", "answer": "Opossum", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5fe8aa9201dd7bf43be5e75d", "question": "In flight systems, what does the initialism \"TCAS\" stand for?", "answer": "Traffic Collision Avoidance System", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b8e8", "question": "What sport features snatches and clean jerks?", "answer": "Weightlifting", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b3d3", "question": "What major British disaster occurred in Beauvais, France, in 1930?", "answer": "Crash of the R101 airship", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133af2c", "question": "When did the Massacre of Glencoe occur?", "answer": "February 12 1692", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a955", "question": "Which European country replaced the Escudo with the Euro?", "answer": "Portugal", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f031133941f", "question": "Which fairytale princess likes sushi in the movie \"Shrek\"?", "answer": "Cinderella", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f03113393d6", "question": "Who danced alongside Shirley Temple in the motion picture \"Captain January\"?", "answer": "Buddy Ebsen", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "591c37cc815febcc896f9274", "question": "What is the third sign of the Zodiac?", "answer": "Gemini", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339c2a", "question": "Who directed the 1939 movie \"The Wizard of Oz\"?", "answer": "Victor Fleming", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b05a", "question": "In what year did Richard Nixon resign as President of the US?", "answer": "1974", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5fecd143ec223966ae8f88be", "question": "What actor wore prosthetic ears while filming \"Jupiter Ascending\"?", "answer": "Channing Tatum", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339dc1", "question": "What double-word song title was a hit single by The Mamas and the Papas?", "answer": "Monday, Monday", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "59a553a03e1c6f9840ba31a6", "question": "In which popular 1950s film is a character played by Audrey Hepburn given 24 hours to do as she pleases in the eternal city?", "answer": "Roman Holiday", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5fe7cd4c877e98cb97778a34", "question": "What was the first country to declare internet a legal right?", "answer": "Finland", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5e72cce8d0874f1a5e2d1c25", "question": "What is a \"Winkle Picker\" or \"Winklepicker\"?", "answer": "An English long pointed shoe", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b68e", "question": "The wide, patterned cravat known as an ascot is properly made of what material?", "answer": "Silk", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f031133952e", "question": "What character did John Goodman play on Roseanne?", "answer": "Dan Conner", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133bbc9", "question": "What country's population hit the one billion mark in May 2000?", "answer": "India", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338c59", "question": "Who was the faithful wife of Ulysses in Homer\u2019s \"Odyssey\"?", "answer": "Penelope", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133abc7", "question": "What is the capital of South Africa?", "answer": "Pretoria", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f03113394e3", "question": "What did Harry Stone wear under his judge's robes on the TV show \"Night Court\"?", "answer": "Blue jeans", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c206", "question": "What year were the Olympic Games hosted in the US for the first time?", "answer": "1904", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a402", "question": "Which city has the world's largest castle complex?", "answer": "Prague, Czech Republic", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5be580ed5415ba52ed6f0abb", "question": "Canada's Maple Leaf national flag was introduced under which Canadian Prime Minister?", "answer": "Lester B. Pearson", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133bebf", "question": "Sepp Blatter and Jack Warner are former executives from which international sports organization?", "answer": "FIFA", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5ff1401eb0ee8c595b6d3995", "question": "Which painting was stolen from the Louvre in 1911 and not returned for over two years?", "answer": "The Mona Lisa", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b65e", "question": "How many of the engines can a 747 pilot see from his cockpit window?", "answer": "None", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f03113392e8", "question": "In the movie \"The Terminator\", what did the cyborg remove in order to repair itself?", "answer": "Its eyeball", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a1d1", "question": "When not fighting crime, what did Underdog do for a living?", "answer": "Shoeshine boy", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "59068253ff9c0647b50a809c", "question": "How much money did buyers interested in Tesla\u2019s Model 3 vehicle, had to pay as a deposit?", "answer": "US$1,000", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338ab9", "question": "What was the first name of Sherlock Holmes' assistant Dr. Watson?", "answer": "John", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f031133917a", "question": "Which Philip K. Dick novelette is the movie \"Total Recall\" based on?", "answer": "We Can Remember It For You Wholesale", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f03113391af", "question": "Who dramatically kissed Halle Berry on stage when he won Best Actor?", "answer": "Adrien Brody", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f03113397a1", "question": "What award winning 1994 Tim Robbins movie was shot at the Ohio State Reformatory?", "answer": "The Shawshank Redemption", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd58de129f03113388a0", "question": "What is the name of Dr. Seuss's egg-hatching elephant?", "answer": "Horton", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f03113391d0", "question": "Who is Ali G?", "answer": "Sacha Baron Cohen", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "6015e539fe83fe1f2a824bba", "question": "Which god is considered the \"destroyer\" and is part of the Hindu Trinity?", "answer": "Shiva", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5fe768e8eec85e375820b2a9", "question": "What is the record snowfall in Phoenix, Arizona?", "answer": "One inch", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "6008e026f4f3bc4a292f862f", "question": "A parody of what song was the first to be used as a NASA wake-up call for astronauts?", "answer": "\u201cHello, Dolly!\u201d (Sent in December 1965 to the crew of Gemini 6, it was retooled \"Hello Wally\" for astronaut Wally Schirra.)", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f03113399e6", "question": "What was the name of the dolphin Ace Ventura was trying to find in the movie \"Ace  Ventura: Pet Detective\"?", "answer": "Snowflake", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5fecc29dec223966ae8f8877", "question": "Which member of boxing\u2019s \"Fabulous Four\" was the only one who defeated each of the other three at least once?", "answer": "Sugar Ray Leonard", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311339227", "question": "What decade did Marty McFly go back to in \"Back to the Future\"?", "answer": "1950's", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5fef93706ce05a3942286e8e", "question": "What is the name of the very cunning and brutal prison warden in the movie \"The Shawshank Redemption\"?", "answer": "Samuel Norton", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f031133948d", "question": "What did Seymour give to Jake as a birthday present in the movie \"One Hour Photo\"?", "answer": "A camera", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5fedd8d66ce05a3942286d75", "question": "Where is the headquarters of Nintendo?", "answer": "Kyoto", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "594d06211a1c922dd1ac64a8", "question": "What year did Robert A. Heinlein published the novel \"The Number of the Beast\"?", "answer": "1980", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5fd9701f23c87fd04dd15e46", "question": "Which President banned Christmas trees from the White House?", "answer": "Theodore Roosevelt", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5ede129f031133c8f2", "question": "A Sone is a unit of what?", "answer": "Loudness", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339fc1", "question": "What genre is Iggy Pop considered to be the grandfather of?", "answer": "Punk", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a1ec", "question": "What year did Guns N' Roses release the album \"The Spaghetti Incident\"?", "answer": "1993", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5bbd4c4000d154d7af00b8d0", "question": "Sir Mix-a-Lot's song \"Baby Got Back\" is also known by what other name?", "answer": "I Like Big Butts", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "6015e07afe83fe1f2a824b8d", "question": "Which Old West figure became sports editor for the \"New York Morning Telegraph?\"", "answer": "William Barclay \"Bat\" Masterson", "category": "history"}, {"id": "59067d13ff9c0647b50a8072", "question": "Which film was the highest-grossing film of 2016?", "answer": "Captain America: Civil War", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b12f", "question": "In 1954, Martin Luther King Jr. became pastor at the Dexter Avenue Baptist Church in what state capital city?", "answer": "Montgomery", "category": "history"}, {"id": "59636f3c967692ea851899b5", "question": "The average American will eat 35,000 what in a lifetime?", "answer": "Cookies", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a701", "question": "Which US state is home to the Inyo Mountains?", "answer": "California", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133ad2f", "question": "Who was the sadistic commander of the HMS Bounty?", "answer": "Captain Bligh", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c63c", "question": "What number is indicated by the Roman Numeral \"D\"?", "answer": "500", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5fe0e52cfcbed638185eaa2b", "question": "The Yalu River separates China from which country?", "answer": "North Korea", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a585", "question": "Which of the New England states is the largest in size?", "answer": "Maine", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a28d", "question": "Who left Metallica to form Megadeth?", "answer": "Dave Mustaine", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338e6c", "question": "Who painted \"The Hibiscus Tree\"?", "answer": "Paul Gauguin", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c7a6", "question": "In which hemisphere can penguins be found?", "answer": "Southern", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f03113395a0", "question": "Which actress played alongside Arnold Schwarzenegger in the 1990 movie \"Total Recall\"?", "answer": "Sharon Stone", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339a49", "question": "Who played the title role in the 1960 film \"Spartacus\"?", "answer": "Kirk Douglas", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5ad7e918b24f84e0b9f9ffc9", "question": "What year did Botswana gain its independence from the United Kingdom?", "answer": "1966", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5fec8b4eec223966ae8f883a", "question": "The movie \"Rush Hour 2\" poked humor at China for consuming which type of animal meat?", "answer": "Dog", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5fec8728ec223966ae8f8813", "question": "What is the astronomical event the astronauts travel through in the film \"Interstellar\"?", "answer": "A wormhole", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f031133a008", "question": "What kind of dog is Pluto's girlfriend, Fifi?", "answer": "Pekingese", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5fd823ebd0de9af39e9d46b5", "question": "What flooded part of Boston in 1919?", "answer": "Molasses", "category": "history"}, {"id": "58d0776d870e6f05ba600863", "question": "What was astronaut Edwin Eugene Aldrin Jr.'s nickname?", "answer": "Buzz", "category": "science"}, {"id": "600cc5cb6de0eb824d4052f4", "question": "What do Spaniards call a bullfight?", "answer": "Corrida", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339df6", "question": "What album spent a record 741 weeks on Billboard's Top 200 Albums chart?", "answer": "Dark Side of the Moon", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5ff14066b0ee8c595b6d399c", "question": "Which 1920s play is the first major play written for children?", "answer": "\"Peter Pan\"", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5b3235f5bf195a31e15d73b4", "question": "Who played the electric piano on the Beatles track \"Get Back\"?", "answer": "Billy Preston", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133aeac", "question": "Who was the second president of the United States?", "answer": "John Adams", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133bc86", "question": "What color is the one-ball in a traditional billiards set?", "answer": "Yellow", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133beba", "question": "What Thames River town lent its name to the collarless polo shirts first worn by its rowing team?", "answer": "Henley", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f031133944c", "question": "Mel Gibson both directed and starred in which 1995 movie?", "answer": "Braveheart", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "591c3677815febcc896f9267", "question": "What does the word \"Desert\" translate as from Latin?", "answer": "An abandoned place", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5bbc933e60f0007efaba0e5b", "question": "What is the name of Hopalong Cassidy's horse?", "answer": "Topper", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b23a", "question": "What royal subject married Anne Boleyn?", "answer": "Henry VIII", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a643", "question": "Trenton is the capital of which US state?", "answer": "New Jersey", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133bb74", "question": "An amendment to the US Constitution must be ratified by what fraction of all the states?", "answer": "75%", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a609", "question": "In which European country is the resort town of Spa?", "answer": "Belgium", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b232", "question": "Who, per her dying wish, is buried next to Wild Bill Hickok?", "answer": "Calamity Jane", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133af9b", "question": "In which year did the Japanese attack Pearl Harbor?", "answer": "1941", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338cc2", "question": "What TV judge wrote the book \"Don't Pee on My Leg and Tell Me It's Raining\"?", "answer": "Judge Judy", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f03113390c8", "question": "Who wrote the play \"L'Alouette\"?", "answer": "Jean Anouilh", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133ab0f", "question": "Which peninsula is Greece located on?", "answer": "Balkan", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133ae11", "question": "Who was Henry VIII's first wife?", "answer": "Catherine of Aragon", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5fefc2176ce05a3942286f19", "question": "In the film \"Dirty Harry,\" what gun does Harry Callahan carry?", "answer": "Smith and Wesson Model 29", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133ad7d", "question": "Which enemy of the Roman Empire was nicknamed the \"Scourge of God\" by the Catholic Church?", "answer": "Attila the Hun", "category": "history"}, {"id": "595247c2736d4be723796b73", "question": "What is the name of Lady Antebellum\u2019s first #1 hit?", "answer": "\"I Run To You\"", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b97b", "question": "What are the names of the three children of Princess Grace of Monaco?", "answer": "Caroline, Albert, Stephanie", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133bcd4", "question": "Baklava is usually made using what kind of paper-thin dough?", "answer": "Filo", "category": "general"}, {"id": "58ab151dbaab681b0929217a", "question": "What year marked the inaugural season of Formula One?", "answer": "1950", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311339337", "question": "How many children did Lucy and Desi have?", "answer": "Two", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339b7f", "question": "Who played Kate Austen on the ABC series \"Lost\"?", "answer": "Evangeline Lilly", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5ffcfd009dc5ec6cd98a8320", "question": "What artist became famous for his pushpin portraits?", "answer": "Eric Daigh (He set a world record by creating a commissioned pushpin piece for automaker Acura, which used 109,687 pushpins.)", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5fd6a8236c0f9723ab15cb63", "question": "What is the best-selling beer in the U.S.?", "answer": "Bud Light", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b215", "question": "Who was assassinated by Carl Weiss?", "answer": "Huey Long", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a613", "question": "Name the largest landlocked country in Europe?", "answer": "Belarus", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "58b0e90f964118b2bb3809c9", "question": "What did Esther Howland popularize in the US?", "answer": "Valentine\u2019s Day greeting cards", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5fefa86a6ce05a3942286ed0", "question": "Who was originally to be cast as Axel Foley in the film \"Beverly Hills Cop\"?", "answer": "Sylvester Stallone", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338c8b", "question": "What was Tom Clancy\u2019s first novel, publisher in 1984?", "answer": "The Hunt for Red October", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311339266", "question": "What is baby Superman called on the planet Krypton?", "answer": "Kal-El", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd58de129f0311338906", "question": "Who wrote the music for the stage version of \"Billy Elliot\"?", "answer": "Elton John", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5fede1246ce05a3942286dc2", "question": "Where is Graceland, the legendary home of Elvis Presley?", "answer": "Memphis, Tennessee", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133ac04", "question": "Yaren is the capital of which country?", "answer": "Nauru", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f03113395d2", "question": "In The Simpsons, who is Lisa's favourite jazz musician?", "answer": "Bleeding Gums Murphy", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5937eb0108d98002fdd633aa", "question": "What are the two cities in Charles Dickens' novel \"A Tale of Two Cities\"?", "answer": "London and Paris", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5fe6a98c20565ad31a57c806", "question": "During World War II, what was the USS Indianapolis' secret mission?", "answer": "Delivering parts for the atomic bomb", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5fec8b44ec223966ae8f8839", "question": "Which cast member of \"The Big Bang Theory\" has a real PhD?", "answer": "Mayim Bialik", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133ba6d", "question": "What is known as Ireland's \"kissing rock\"?", "answer": "The Blarney Stone", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5fefc1bc6ce05a3942286f14", "question": "Lee Marvin won an Oscar for his role in what movie?", "answer": "Cat Ballou", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c48d", "question": "What does an ornithologist study?", "answer": "Birds", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c3e3", "question": "What is kept in a ship's binnacle?", "answer": "Compass", "category": "science"}, {"id": "58be2d7d8faf425cf37add7f", "question": "The game \"Cities: Skylines\" was developed by which Finnish video game company?", "answer": "Colossal Order", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c1c5", "question": "What is the only sign in the zodiac which is not represented by a living thing?", "answer": "Libra", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5ede129f031133ca92", "question": "Kiwano is a type of what?", "answer": "Fruit", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5fede1f96ce05a3942286dc9", "question": "Which \"Margaritaville\" singer was born on Christmas in 1946?", "answer": "Jimmy Buffett", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5fd2d6552596a59cbdfbd3a9", "question": "What is the world's largest machine?", "answer": "The large hadron collider (LHC)", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133bddb", "question": "What sport's most famous series is played for the Ashes urn?", "answer": "Cricket's", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5febbc557e83c707845b214b", "question": "Which NFL player later went on to become a US Supreme Court Judge?", "answer": "Byron White who was a runner-up to the Heisman Trophy in 1937, served as an Associate Supreme Court Justice from 1962 to 1993.", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a989", "question": "What city named its airport after Ayatollah Khomeini?", "answer": "Teheran", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f031133a05b", "question": "What is the name of Amy Winehouse's first album?", "answer": "Frank", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a6b0", "question": "The US has shoreline along which oceans?", "answer": "Atlantic, Arctic and Pacific", "category": "geography"}]